Live. Die. Repeat.
Edge of Tomorrow is a action, science fiction film directed by Doug Liman.
Major Bill Cage is an officer who has never seen a day of combat when
he is unceremoniously demoted and dropped into combat.
Cage is killed within minutes, managing to take an alpha alien down with him.
He awakens back at the beginning of the same day and
is forced to fight and die again...
and again - as physical contact with the alien has thrown him into a time loop.
Cage, played by Tom Cruise.
Rita, played by Emily Blunt.
General Brigham, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Master Sergeant Farell, played by Bill Paxton.
Skinner, played by Jonas Armstrong.
Kimmel, played by Tony Way.
Edge of Tomorrow is a 2014 American science fiction action
film starring Tom Cruise and Emily Blunt.
Directed by Doug Liman and written by Christopher McQuarrie, Jez Butterworth and John-Henry
Butterworth, it is based on the Japanese light novel All You Need Is Kill by Hiroshi Sakurazaka.
The film takes place in a future where most of Europe is
occupied by an alien race known as mimics.
Major William Cage (Cruise), a public relations officer with no combat experience, is forced by his superiors to join a landing
operation against the aliens, only to find himself experiencing a time loop as he tries to find a way to defeat the mimics.
Bill Paxton and Brendan Gleeson appear in supporting roles.
In late 2009, 3 Arts Entertainment purchased the rights to All You
Need Is Kill and sold the spec script to Warner Bros.
The studio produced Edge of Tomorrow with the involvement of 3 Arts, the novel's
publisher Viz Media, and Australian production company Village Roadshow.
Filming began in late 2012, taking place in England: at Warner Bros.
Studios in Leavesden, outside London, and other locations, such as
London's Trafalgar Square and the coastal Saunton Sands.
A total of nine companies handled the visual effects.
Edge of Tomorrow was released theatrically in select territories on
May 30, 2014, and in the United States on June 6.
The film received positive reviews from critics, and grossed
$370 million against a $178 million budget.
The film explores themes of deja vu, based on novel or
book, restart, military officer, dystopia.
The tone is thought_provoking.